<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/blog</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/blog"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2018-02-06T18:55:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Was the XIV &amp; SVXY Blow Up Caused by Malicious Market Manipulation?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2018/02/06/xiv-blowup-market-manipulation/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2018/02/06/xiv-blowup-market-manipulation/</id>
    <published>2018-02-06T18:55:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2018-02-06T19:23:20-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2018/20180206c.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2018/20180206c.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday the popular inverse volatility funds XIV and SVXY both imploded in the afterhours market. Due to the decline,
Credit Suisse is recalling the XIV note. Meanwhile, SVXY opened for trading down over 80% from yesterday's close. All
of this happened due to the largest single-day rise in the VIX ever seen in its history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a chart showing the biggest VIX spikes since its inception. Note that on 8/24/15 the VIX also had a very
bad day, but the inverse funds did not blow up. I believe this is because XIV and SVXY's intrinsic value is
derived from the CBOE traded VIX Futures contract, which correlate to VIX movements but tend to lag somewhat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2018/20180206a.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2018/20180206a.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spike in the VIX was insanely unusual because not even during the 2008 financial crisis have we seen
such a large intraday move. Since the VIX value is derived from the premiums of stock options, could algorithmic
program trading have contributed to this unusual rise?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2018/20180206b.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2018/20180206b.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I found personally alarming about this event is that these securities closed down business as usual
on a declining day for the stock market. It was a losing day, but at the close there was no indication it
would be a day that the fund would lose &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of its value. The destructive event happened in the after hours
market, when the VIX futures, which are held by both funds, suddenly spiked, causing a liquidity crisis. Because
both XIV and SVXY emulate the daily returns of being short the VIX futures, a 100% increase pretty much wipes
out the value of these funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 4pm ET the February CBOE VIX Futures contract was trading around 22, but immediately after the close there was a
sudden spike to 33, which is what broke the XIV and SVXY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2018/20180206f.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2018/20180206f.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I find so strange about this is that yesterday's decline in the stock market was not unusual for a
correction by any means. Yes, it was harsh, but the S&amp;amp;P 500 index has seen much worse down days without a volatility
spike like this (especially in the afterhours). Could it be that the XIV/SVXY was specifically targeted for
breakage? Was someone sitting on a lot of money waiting for a day with a volaility spike to push the futures
over the edge, beyond a 100% move in the afterhours when the trading volume is light? Traders with size do this
all the time. Sometimes big traders will nudge individual stocks or indexes to certain price points to take out
the stops of other market participants, causing larger moves or taking advantage of the liquidity for a trade
positioned the opposite way. It's not inconceivable that the VIX futures was targeted using a similar scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether or not this was the doing of a bad actor, because this happened it will probably happen again.  Credit
Suisse not plans to recall the XIV ETN, but it was such a popular product that I have no doubt it will return
soon in some form. Thankfully, the bank was fully hedged. I hope that when it does comes back, they will have some
protection in place to safeguard against this type of after hours event from repeating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2018/20180206d.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2018/20180206d.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2018/20180206e.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2018/20180206e.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Shut Down of MomentumStockScans.com and USTreasuryYieldCurve.com</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/09/05/shutting-down-momo-scans-and-ustreasurycurve/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/09/05/shutting-down-momo-scans-and-ustreasurycurve/</id>
    <published>2017-09-05T19:55:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-05T22:18:16-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am temporarily shutting down my websites momentumstockscans.com and ustreasuryyieldcurve.com. I initially thought
these websites would generate sufficient traffic to be self-sustainable from ad revenue, but at the moment they
are unprofitable. Both websites require their own databases and run via Docker containers hosted on AWS, which gets
costly. I will put the websites back up as they were once I find a more cost effective hosting solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Trump Bull Market is NOT Over!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/06/30/trump-bull-market-is-not-over/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/06/30/trump-bull-market-is-not-over/</id>
    <published>2017-06-29T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-30T22:37:30-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;2017 has been a disappointing year for the kind of trader who thrives on volatility! The VIX has been stuck near
historic lows, and ever since President Trump has been elected every dip in the market has been a bear trap. How much
farther can it go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-old-is-the-bull"&gt;How Old is the Bull?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I frequently see interviews where the talking heads on finance TV shows mention how the bull market has been going on
for 8 years and is due to end soon. (&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-QhHkRFtDUM&amp;amp;t=446s" target="_blank"&gt;Here's one such interview&lt;/a&gt;)
There's a common thread of thought that a bull market typically lasts 5-7 years before a bear market. The media often
considers any prolonged decline in the S&amp;amp;P500 of 20% or greater to be a "bear market", while a 10% decline
is referred to as a "correction".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does the current bull market really compare to previous bull markets? I went back to S&amp;amp;P500 charts since 1993
noting all the major advances and declines from the market peak to the market bottom. Several long-lasting corrections
such as the 2016 multiple-dip in the market in which the S&amp;amp;P 500 declined 15% I counted as a bear market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__4_22_PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__4_22_PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 1: Bull &amp;amp; Bear Markets
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the typical bull market lasts an average of 172 weeks and the S&amp;amp;P 500 average advance is between 36%
and 173%, with the average gain of 89%. By this measure, the Trump bull market, which actually began with the S&amp;amp;P500
bottom of 1810 in February of 2016, is still fairly young at 72 weeks and up 35%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if we stick with the strict definition of a bear market being a 20% decline? The Trump bull market still
has room to run by historical standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__5_01_PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__5_01_PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 2: Bull &amp;amp; Bear Markets - strict definition
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But using the strict 20% decline as a delimiter for bull/bear markets, the typical bull market is even more robust,
lasting an average of 231 weeks and advancing between 68% and 304%, with the average gain of 142%. By this measure
the current bull market is 299 weeks old and counting, with an advance of 128% in the S&amp;amp;P500 index. While still
a long-lasting bull, it is by no means unusual and could still continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 20% bear market definition also puts the current bull market's beginning back to the debt crisis of 2011. When people
on the television say that the bull market began in 2009, they are conveniently forgetting the rough patch we hit in 2011
when the US Treasury debt was downgraded over Congress's debt ceiling debate. There were also many concerns at the time
that economic growth was weak and that the economy would slip back into the Great Recession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My opinion is that the market's choppy ride from August 2015 through February 2016, while not quite a bear market,
was a healthy rotation of money that shook out all the weak hands and set up the building of a new bull market.
Remember, the stock market has behaved quite differently ever since the 2016 election season ended - as if the election
was a catalyst for the next big stock market move up. In historical context, I believe this action looks most similar
to the 1994 choppy market where stock prices were stuck in a volatile range, then 1995 abruptly opened
the start of one of the stock market's biggest bull market runs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_d.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_d.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 3: The 1995 bull market began on the heels of a choppy 1994
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_b.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_b.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 4: The Trump bull market if you consider the election to be the start
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__7_32_PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__7_32_PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 5: The Trump bull market thus far in comparison to 1994-1995
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class="momo_scans_ad"&gt;Be sure to check out my FREE stock scanning service &lt;a href="http://www.momentumstockscans.com/"&gt;Momentum Stock Scans.com&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id="is-vix-complacency-a-concern"&gt;Is VIX Complacency a Concern?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I find odd about about the current state of the market is the historically low VIX. It's hard to believe that
a little over a year ago investors were spooked over Brexit and there seemed to be widespread fear. Now we are at a
historical level of complacency. Might this signal the stock market as being too optimistic about the fundamentals?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last time the VIX achieved a historic low as the summer of 2014. Not long after that we had a correction of 10%
in the fall, but the market still rallied to new highs after that correction. Although, the correction following
was a big one and the market choppy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 6: Depiction of 2014 VIX all time low
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time before that the VIX hit a historic low in the fall of 2006. Similar story… a correction followed not long
after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_c.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_c.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 7: Depiction of 2014 VIX all time low
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not saying it's going to play out exactly the same way this time, but a historically low VIX does seem to mark
the pendulum swinging too far into the territory of complacency. The good news is that it does not necessarily signal
a top in the S&amp;amp;P500 and history seems to show that you have a good 12-18 months left in the bull market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async="" src="//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;!-- article-middle --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:inline-block;width:336px;height:280px" data-ad-client="ca-pub-9623179230776920" data-ad-slot="8025628292"&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
  (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="could-complacency-set-up-for-a-bigger-crash"&gt;Could Complacency Set Up for a Bigger Crash?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the 2016 election, the market hasn't even had as much as a regression of 4.0% from the new highs, which is unusual,
and follows the trend of shrinking intensity of corrections from 2015. A correction of 6-10% seems due, and we may even see
a reversal of this trend as we head into the next bear market and economic cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__8_41_PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__8_41_PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 8: Pullbacks from the S&amp;amp;P500 highs have been getting shallower as of late. This chart excludes bear markets because the S&amp;amp;P500 tops out and the market steadily drops for a more lengthy period of time. (I count the 2015-2016 choppy period as a bear market.)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a bear market begins, it will happen gradually. The S&amp;amp;P500 will struggle to make new highs and we will see a widening
of price swings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous Bear Markets last on average 60 weeks from peak to bottom, giving you plenty of time to get out early. The following
chart shows that entering a bear market you have many large price fluctuations exceeding 8%. The market rarely drops
20% out of the blue without prior warning signs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__9_20_PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__9_20_PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 9: Large price swings seem to precede bear markets
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_e.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_e.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 10: The 2008 bear market was characterized by a series of lower highs before the big Lehman Brothers crash
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script async="" src="//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;!-- article-middle --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:inline-block;width:336px;height:280px" data-ad-client="ca-pub-9623179230776920" data-ad-slot="8025628292"&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
  (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Given the age and advance of the "Trump bull market" by various historical comparisons, there is still plenty of
upside in the S&amp;amp;P500 over the next 12-18 months.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The complacency signaled by the VIX may signal a correction of 7-12% occuring sometime later this year, but the
bull market can resume shortly after.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are overdue for a pullback from the all time highs, given that the largest pullback from the highs since
the 2016 was only 3.1%.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A "bear market" (drop of over 20% from the S&amp;amp;P 500 highs) seems unlikely, and even if we were to enter
a bear market there would be plenty of warning signs in the form of lower highs on the major indices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that corporate earnings ultimately drive valuations and for now the fundamental outlook appears strong.
There is no reason to think corporate growth will meaningfully shrink over the next 12 months. Industry
professionals seem to remain optimistic about global and domestic growth. In &lt;a href="https://www.nuveen.com/Commentary/BobDoll/WeeklyCommentary.aspx?utm_source=SilverpopMailing&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=20170227_BobDoll_201702Template%20(17)&amp;amp;spMailingID=11293632&amp;amp;spUserID=MTc0NzU3MzEyMTIxS0&amp;amp;spJobID=1181639680&amp;amp;spReportId=MTE4MTYzOTY4MAS2" target="_blank"&gt;Bob Doll's recent Weekly Commentary&lt;/a&gt;, he writes that
second quarter US domestic growth could reach 3%, and expects corporate earnings to remain strong.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Introducing MomentumStockScans.com!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/06/25/introducing-momentum-stock-scans/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/06/25/introducing-momentum-stock-scans/</id>
    <published>2017-06-24T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-25T12:31:18-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here is a link to my latest project, &lt;a href="http://www.momentumstockscans.com"&gt;MomentumStockScans.com&lt;/a&gt;, a free stock market
scanning tool to help equities traders find the best daily opportunities. Here is a brief introduction video,
more content to follow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pgX9ws8k6uY" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Introducing the US Treasury Yield Curve Website!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/06/07/new-website-us-treasury-yield-curve/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/06/07/new-website-us-treasury-yield-curve/</id>
    <published>2017-06-06T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-07T18:24:05-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I haven't been posting to this much, but I created a new website related to trading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ustreasuryyieldcurve.com"&gt;ustreasuryyieldcurve.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be a useful reference for seeing the state of interest rates and what they might signal for the economy.
Worth checking every so often!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>XIV is About to Get Dangerous</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2015/09/29/xiv-is-about-to-get-dangerous/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2015/09/29/xiv-is-about-to-get-dangerous/</id>
    <published>2015-09-28T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-30T22:41:03-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For a long time I have been an advocate of the long XIV trade, or effectively, to short any volatility spikes. This strategy has worked very well during the most recent bull market. Who wouldn't be lured by the tenfold gain seen on the XIV chart?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2015/09/Main_thinkorswim__build_1878_29_.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2015/09/Main_thinkorswim__build_1878_29_.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      XIV nicely weathered every dip since 2011. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: ThinkOrSwim&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, past performance is not predictive of future returns. XIV has been smashed by this recent rout in the market, having fallen over 50% from its all time high. In fact, the XIV trade does not seem to be working well in general lately. It's price has had some wild swings since the fourth quarter of 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Happened to Contango?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I &lt;a title="Is now a good time to buy XIV?" href="http://www.greenspudtrades.com/2014/09/29/is-now-a-good-time-to-buy-xiv/"&gt;explained in a post last year&lt;/a&gt;, XIV's returns have been supercharged by a prolonged period of backwardation on the CBOE VIX futures curve. Then early this year I wrote a&lt;a title="The Dangers of Swing Trading XIV" href="http://www.greenspudtrades.com/2015/01/02/the-dangers-of-swing-trading-xiv/"&gt; follow up to that post when I noticed&lt;/a&gt; that XIV seemed to have broken its long term trend. I put forth several reasons that we may be entering a new phase of volatility where the persistence of contango helping the XIV may no longer be so reliable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the stock market began its correction at the end of August, XIV has been hurting because the futures curve is stuck in backwardation. Unlike most volatility spikes in recent years, this time the VIX and backwardation are not fading so quickly. To better understand how this could impact XIV, I conducted a study of past "sticky" volatility spikes to determine if we could gain insight into the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this study, I make the assumption that any VIX spike above its long term average will send the VIX futures curve into backwardation. This will happen because the price of the nearest expiring futures contract is drawn to the spot price of the VIX, but longer dated futures contracts are drawn to the VIX long term average. The difference between the current VIX futures contract and the spot is what traders call the roll yield. &lt;a href="http://vixcontango.com/Site/Introduction#VolatilityCurveFormations"&gt;This blog article by VIX Contango Oscillator explains it very well&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;...a VIX Future contract over the long term tries to reach the average spot VIX value. The farther out in time the future, the closer the fair value will be to the average historical VIX value. The delta between the future price approximation and the average value goes exponentially closer to zero. The flipside of that calculation is that the nearest term VIX future has the largest difference to the long-term average, the second term VIX Future - the second largest difference, the third term VIX Future - the third largest difference, etc. The exponential decline in the delta can be plainly seen in the usual VIX Future Curve formation depicted above (Contango formation).&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2015/09/Pasted_Image_9_29_15__11_22_PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2015/09/Pasted_Image_9_29_15__11_22_PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2015/09/Pasted_Image_9_29_15__11_27_PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2015/09/Pasted_Image_9_29_15__11_27_PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I downloaded the historical spot VIX prices from the &lt;a href="http://www.cboe.com/micro/vix/historical.aspx"&gt;CBOE website&lt;/a&gt;.  Using data from 2004-2015, I calculated the average value based upon the daily closes to be &lt;strong&gt;19.4&lt;/strong&gt;. Next, I wanted to determine how often and the length of intervals that the VIX spends above its long term average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My theory is that when the VIX is above the long term average, the short term VIX futures is more likely to be in a state of backwardation. Backwardation is harmful to XIV. Therefore, prolonged periods of time when the VIX remains above 19.4 should be very detrimental to the price of XIV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class="momo_scans_ad"&gt;Be sure to check out my FREE stock scanning service &lt;a href="http://www.momentumstockscans.com/"&gt;Momentum Stock Scans.com&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Study Findings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 2004-2015, I learned that the VIX spent roughly 1/3 of its time above the long term average. The median of 16.4 indicates that the distribution of where the VIX spends its time is skewed upward. In other words, a fewer number of high VIX days during spikes has pulled the average higher.  This would explain how the VIX futures could spend more days in contango than backwardation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-09-28-at-3.53.57-PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-09-28-at-3.53.57-PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Source: Derived from CBOE Figures&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The longevity and distribution of VIX spikes is most interesting. I noted the length of periods when the VIX went above its long term average and held for a number of days. As expected, tumultuous times in the market correlated to longer periods of an elevated VIX. Here are key periods of time when the VIX went above its long term average of 19.4 and held. (I only analyzed whether the VIX was above or below 19.4; point value of much was not examined.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-09-28-at-4.16.03-PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-09-28-at-4.16.03-PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then grouped each period of high volatility into year and quarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-09-28-at-4.23.58-PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-09-28-at-4.23.58-PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Percentage of days within each quarter where the VIX was above its long term average of 19.4
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This table shows that the VIX is polarizing! During tumultuous times the VIX could remain elevated for extensive periods, which is very bad for XIV. In 2009, the VIX stayed above its long term average for the entire year. But during periods when the markets are relatively calm such as 2004-2006, the VIX won't spend more than a few days at a time above its long term average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XIV was launched just before a period of historically low volatility. This has given the dangerous illusion that XIV is invulnerable and will always be driven higher by contango, which is not always the case. The only time we've really gotten a taste of how prolonged volatility affects XIV is 2011 when it took a 75% drawdown during the debt ceiling crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2015/09/Main_thinkorswim__build_1878_29_1.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2015/09/Main_thinkorswim__build_1878_29_1.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Teal shaded periods denote VIX &amp;gt; 19.4. &lt;strong&gt;Source: ThinkOrSwim&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2015/09/Main_thinkorswim__build_1878_29_2.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2015/09/Main_thinkorswim__build_1878_29_2.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is possible to use the SPVXSP index to backtrack the theoretical performance of the XIV before it was created, as &lt;a href="http://onlyvix.blogspot.com/2011/06/xiv-first-6-months.html"&gt;described on this other blog&lt;/a&gt;. If only more traders had this view of the XIV during the 2008 financial crisis, perhaps it would be less appealing. As the author states, if you model the performance of XIV back to 2006, you will see that it would have lost 80% of its value at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-09-28-at-6.53.07-PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-09-28-at-6.53.07-PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Source: onlyvix.blogspot.com
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script async="" src="//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;!-- article-middle --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:inline-block;width:336px;height:280px" data-ad-client="ca-pub-9623179230776920" data-ad-slot="8025628292"&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
  (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where can XIV go from here?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use a proprietary model to estimate potential future prices for XIV based on percentage changes in the underlying VIX futures prices (months 1 and 2). As of today, my model indicates that the current effective price for the XIV's underlying VIX futures is 23.63. If in one day the VIX futures months 1 and 2 mix were to move to an average of 30, we could see XIV dip into the upper teens. The good news is that if volatility were to somehow go away and drop back to ~14, we could see XIV rally into the upper 30s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-09-28-at-7.04.15-PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-09-28-at-7.04.15-PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as we can see from the charts above, "sticky" backwardation can happen when the VIX finds support above its long term average, causing XIV to get hammered. I see this scenario as likely until near end of the year at best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How I'm Trading This&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2015/09/Main_thinkorswim__build_1878_29_3.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2015/09/Main_thinkorswim__build_1878_29_3.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quickness and severity of the current VIX spike caught me by surprise. I was sitting on a small position from the upper 40's. When it gapped down and settled into the 20s I began building a more serious position. My plan was to add the rest of my intended shares upon any sign that the VIX was receding as usual, but that didn't happen yet. In fact, I made a mistake by buying into the fakeout rally following the most recent FOMC meeting, hurting my average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My research now tells me that since we are nearing 30 days with the VIX holding steady in the 20s, we may be in for a much longer volatility ride. This will not bode well for XIV. Until the S&amp;amp;P 500 reclaims the 2000 level, the VIX retreats back into the teens, and/or the VIX fades below the 200DMA, I do not think XIV is going to generate stellar positive returns. Judging by the length of past market corrections, I would venture to guess that the VIX can remain elevated for another quarter or more. Therefore, I will be reducing my size into rallies and looking to buy back at a better cost average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my personal weaknesses as a trader is that I am often too early in acting on an idea. Executing too early will get you a bad entry. With my buying power tied up through premature trades, I will not be able to buy more shares unless I unload some. I certainly don't want to be heavy handed in XIV if the S&amp;amp;P500 falls to its next level of support at 1810.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2015/09/Main_thinkorswim__build_1876_16_.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2015/09/Main_thinkorswim__build_1876_16_.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Word&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XIV inverse volatility is a compelling instrument. It's extreme performance over the last several years has caught the attention of many traders. However, the recent changes in the patterns of the VIX lead me to believe we are entering a new period of increased volatility, which would be harmful to XIV as a long term holding. Use caution when building a position as long as the VIX is supported above its long term average of ~20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
