<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/blog</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/blog"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2018-03-17T19:55:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>SVXY - The Volatility Party is Over</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2018/03/17/svxy-the-volatility-party-is-over/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2018/03/17/svxy-the-volatility-party-is-over/</id>
    <published>2018-03-17T19:55:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-17T23:19:29-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the XIV exchange traded note gone, fans of trading inverse volatility will be looking to SVXY as an alternative.
Unforunately on February 27, ProShares has announced that they will &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2018/02/27/firm-swoops-in-to-ensure-volatility-is-a-trade-for-another-day.html"&gt;reduce the leverage in the SVXY product from 1 to
0.5&lt;/a&gt;. This means
that whereas before SVXY tracked the inverse daily moves of the CBOT VIX futures month 1 and 2 contracts 1-to-1,
a move in the VIX futures values will now result in half that percentage move in the SVXY. So let's say that
there's a 5% down move in the VIX futures contracts, the SVXY would only change in value by a 2.5% up move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2018/20180317a.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2018/20180317a.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This change in leverage is a wise move for ProShares, the company issuing the SVXY security, because it means that
an unprecedented move in volatility as we saw in early February is less likely to wipe out the fund's assets. But this
is detrimental to investors looking to capitalize on contango and it's compounding effect on the security. Here's a
chart I put together showing what sort of gains you would get if you invested $100,000 in SVXY and held for 30 days
while contango was at 9% from the month 1 to month 2 rollover and the average value of the VIX contracts remained the
same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2018/20180317a.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2018/20180317a.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 2
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You actually get a little bit more than a 9% return because the investment compounds. At 50% leverage, you will make
4.4%, less than have the return. I tried experimenting with what would happen if you tried to compensate for the lower
leverage by doubling your position size in SVXY. As you can see in the third column, it's not quite the same
because there's less compounding and you fall short in nominal return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doubling your exposure in SVXY to achieve the same return is dangerous because you have more capital at risk. Have
a look at this chart depicting 4 consecutive days of 20% rise in VIX future contracts. At 100% leverage, SVXY
starting at a value of 100 would decline 20% per day, ending the 4-day streak to end at a value of 40.96. At 50%
leverage, the decline woudn't be quite as bad as it would end at 34.49.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2018/20180317a.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2018/20180317a.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 3
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let's say you doubled your exposure, trying to replicate the same old returns. In this type of multi-day decline
you would nominally lose more dollar amount (68.78) versus the 59.04 you would have lost with the old SVXY. That's about
a 16.5% higher loss than you would have gotten before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that XIV/SVXY was too good to be true. Thanks to the demise of XIV and change in leverage of SVXY, never again
will we have such a good vehicle for profiting from the VIX futures contango. Your best bet going forward for this kind
of trade is to short VXX… but use position sizes wisely and hedge to protect your account from margin calls!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Was the XIV &amp; SVXY Blow Up Caused by Malicious Market Manipulation?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2018/02/06/xiv-blowup-market-manipulation/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2018/02/06/xiv-blowup-market-manipulation/</id>
    <published>2018-02-06T18:55:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2018-02-06T19:23:20-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2018/20180206c.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2018/20180206c.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday the popular inverse volatility funds XIV and SVXY both imploded in the afterhours market. Due to the decline,
Credit Suisse is recalling the XIV note. Meanwhile, SVXY opened for trading down over 80% from yesterday's close. All
of this happened due to the largest single-day rise in the VIX ever seen in its history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a chart showing the biggest VIX spikes since its inception. Note that on 8/24/15 the VIX also had a very
bad day, but the inverse funds did not blow up. I believe this is because XIV and SVXY's intrinsic value is
derived from the CBOE traded VIX Futures contract, which correlate to VIX movements but tend to lag somewhat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2018/20180206a.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2018/20180206a.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spike in the VIX was insanely unusual because not even during the 2008 financial crisis have we seen
such a large intraday move. Since the VIX value is derived from the premiums of stock options, could algorithmic
program trading have contributed to this unusual rise?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2018/20180206b.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2018/20180206b.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I found personally alarming about this event is that these securities closed down business as usual
on a declining day for the stock market. It was a losing day, but at the close there was no indication it
would be a day that the fund would lose &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of its value. The destructive event happened in the after hours
market, when the VIX futures, which are held by both funds, suddenly spiked, causing a liquidity crisis. Because
both XIV and SVXY emulate the daily returns of being short the VIX futures, a 100% increase pretty much wipes
out the value of these funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 4pm ET the February CBOE VIX Futures contract was trading around 22, but immediately after the close there was a
sudden spike to 33, which is what broke the XIV and SVXY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2018/20180206f.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2018/20180206f.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I find so strange about this is that yesterday's decline in the stock market was not unusual for a
correction by any means. Yes, it was harsh, but the S&amp;amp;P 500 index has seen much worse down days without a volatility
spike like this (especially in the afterhours). Could it be that the XIV/SVXY was specifically targeted for
breakage? Was someone sitting on a lot of money waiting for a day with a volaility spike to push the futures
over the edge, beyond a 100% move in the afterhours when the trading volume is light? Traders with size do this
all the time. Sometimes big traders will nudge individual stocks or indexes to certain price points to take out
the stops of other market participants, causing larger moves or taking advantage of the liquidity for a trade
positioned the opposite way. It's not inconceivable that the VIX futures was targeted using a similar scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether or not this was the doing of a bad actor, because this happened it will probably happen again.  Credit
Suisse not plans to recall the XIV ETN, but it was such a popular product that I have no doubt it will return
soon in some form. Thankfully, the bank was fully hedged. I hope that when it does comes back, they will have some
protection in place to safeguard against this type of after hours event from repeating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2018/20180206d.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2018/20180206d.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2018/20180206e.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2018/20180206e.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Shut Down of MomentumStockScans.com and USTreasuryYieldCurve.com</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/09/05/shutting-down-momo-scans-and-ustreasurycurve/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/09/05/shutting-down-momo-scans-and-ustreasurycurve/</id>
    <published>2017-09-05T19:55:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-05T22:18:16-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am temporarily shutting down my websites momentumstockscans.com and ustreasuryyieldcurve.com. I initially thought
these websites would generate sufficient traffic to be self-sustainable from ad revenue, but at the moment they
are unprofitable. Both websites require their own databases and run via Docker containers hosted on AWS, which gets
costly. I will put the websites back up as they were once I find a more cost effective hosting solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Trump Bull Market is NOT Over!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/06/30/trump-bull-market-is-not-over/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/06/30/trump-bull-market-is-not-over/</id>
    <published>2017-06-29T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-30T22:37:30-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;2017 has been a disappointing year for the kind of trader who thrives on volatility! The VIX has been stuck near
historic lows, and ever since President Trump has been elected every dip in the market has been a bear trap. How much
farther can it go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-old-is-the-bull"&gt;How Old is the Bull?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I frequently see interviews where the talking heads on finance TV shows mention how the bull market has been going on
for 8 years and is due to end soon. (&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-QhHkRFtDUM&amp;amp;t=446s" target="_blank"&gt;Here's one such interview&lt;/a&gt;)
There's a common thread of thought that a bull market typically lasts 5-7 years before a bear market. The media often
considers any prolonged decline in the S&amp;amp;P500 of 20% or greater to be a "bear market", while a 10% decline
is referred to as a "correction".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does the current bull market really compare to previous bull markets? I went back to S&amp;amp;P500 charts since 1993
noting all the major advances and declines from the market peak to the market bottom. Several long-lasting corrections
such as the 2016 multiple-dip in the market in which the S&amp;amp;P 500 declined 15% I counted as a bear market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__4_22_PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__4_22_PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 1: Bull &amp;amp; Bear Markets
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the typical bull market lasts an average of 172 weeks and the S&amp;amp;P 500 average advance is between 36%
and 173%, with the average gain of 89%. By this measure, the Trump bull market, which actually began with the S&amp;amp;P500
bottom of 1810 in February of 2016, is still fairly young at 72 weeks and up 35%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if we stick with the strict definition of a bear market being a 20% decline? The Trump bull market still
has room to run by historical standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__5_01_PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__5_01_PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 2: Bull &amp;amp; Bear Markets - strict definition
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But using the strict 20% decline as a delimiter for bull/bear markets, the typical bull market is even more robust,
lasting an average of 231 weeks and advancing between 68% and 304%, with the average gain of 142%. By this measure
the current bull market is 299 weeks old and counting, with an advance of 128% in the S&amp;amp;P500 index. While still
a long-lasting bull, it is by no means unusual and could still continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 20% bear market definition also puts the current bull market's beginning back to the debt crisis of 2011. When people
on the television say that the bull market began in 2009, they are conveniently forgetting the rough patch we hit in 2011
when the US Treasury debt was downgraded over Congress's debt ceiling debate. There were also many concerns at the time
that economic growth was weak and that the economy would slip back into the Great Recession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My opinion is that the market's choppy ride from August 2015 through February 2016, while not quite a bear market,
was a healthy rotation of money that shook out all the weak hands and set up the building of a new bull market.
Remember, the stock market has behaved quite differently ever since the 2016 election season ended - as if the election
was a catalyst for the next big stock market move up. In historical context, I believe this action looks most similar
to the 1994 choppy market where stock prices were stuck in a volatile range, then 1995 abruptly opened
the start of one of the stock market's biggest bull market runs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_d.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_d.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 3: The 1995 bull market began on the heels of a choppy 1994
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_b.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_b.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 4: The Trump bull market if you consider the election to be the start
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__7_32_PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__7_32_PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 5: The Trump bull market thus far in comparison to 1994-1995
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class="momo_scans_ad"&gt;Be sure to check out my FREE stock scanning service &lt;a href="http://www.momentumstockscans.com/"&gt;Momentum Stock Scans.com&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id="is-vix-complacency-a-concern"&gt;Is VIX Complacency a Concern?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I find odd about about the current state of the market is the historically low VIX. It's hard to believe that
a little over a year ago investors were spooked over Brexit and there seemed to be widespread fear. Now we are at a
historical level of complacency. Might this signal the stock market as being too optimistic about the fundamentals?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last time the VIX achieved a historic low as the summer of 2014. Not long after that we had a correction of 10%
in the fall, but the market still rallied to new highs after that correction. Although, the correction following
was a big one and the market choppy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 6: Depiction of 2014 VIX all time low
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time before that the VIX hit a historic low in the fall of 2006. Similar story… a correction followed not long
after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_c.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_c.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 7: Depiction of 2014 VIX all time low
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not saying it's going to play out exactly the same way this time, but a historically low VIX does seem to mark
the pendulum swinging too far into the territory of complacency. The good news is that it does not necessarily signal
a top in the S&amp;amp;P500 and history seems to show that you have a good 12-18 months left in the bull market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async="" src="//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;!-- article-middle --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:inline-block;width:336px;height:280px" data-ad-client="ca-pub-9623179230776920" data-ad-slot="8025628292"&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
  (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="could-complacency-set-up-for-a-bigger-crash"&gt;Could Complacency Set Up for a Bigger Crash?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the 2016 election, the market hasn't even had as much as a regression of 4.0% from the new highs, which is unusual,
and follows the trend of shrinking intensity of corrections from 2015. A correction of 6-10% seems due, and we may even see
a reversal of this trend as we head into the next bear market and economic cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__8_41_PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__8_41_PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 8: Pullbacks from the S&amp;amp;P500 highs have been getting shallower as of late. This chart excludes bear markets because the S&amp;amp;P500 tops out and the market steadily drops for a more lengthy period of time. (I count the 2015-2016 choppy period as a bear market.)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a bear market begins, it will happen gradually. The S&amp;amp;P500 will struggle to make new highs and we will see a widening
of price swings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous Bear Markets last on average 60 weeks from peak to bottom, giving you plenty of time to get out early. The following
chart shows that entering a bear market you have many large price fluctuations exceeding 8%. The market rarely drops
20% out of the blue without prior warning signs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__9_20_PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Pasted_Image_6_30_17__9_20_PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 9: Large price swings seem to precede bear markets
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_e.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2017/06/Main_thinkorswim__build_1902_8_e.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Figure 10: The 2008 bear market was characterized by a series of lower highs before the big Lehman Brothers crash
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script async="" src="//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;!-- article-middle --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:inline-block;width:336px;height:280px" data-ad-client="ca-pub-9623179230776920" data-ad-slot="8025628292"&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
  (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Given the age and advance of the "Trump bull market" by various historical comparisons, there is still plenty of
upside in the S&amp;amp;P500 over the next 12-18 months.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The complacency signaled by the VIX may signal a correction of 7-12% occuring sometime later this year, but the
bull market can resume shortly after.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are overdue for a pullback from the all time highs, given that the largest pullback from the highs since
the 2016 was only 3.1%.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A "bear market" (drop of over 20% from the S&amp;amp;P 500 highs) seems unlikely, and even if we were to enter
a bear market there would be plenty of warning signs in the form of lower highs on the major indices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that corporate earnings ultimately drive valuations and for now the fundamental outlook appears strong.
There is no reason to think corporate growth will meaningfully shrink over the next 12 months. Industry
professionals seem to remain optimistic about global and domestic growth. In &lt;a href="https://www.nuveen.com/Commentary/BobDoll/WeeklyCommentary.aspx?utm_source=SilverpopMailing&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=20170227_BobDoll_201702Template%20(17)&amp;amp;spMailingID=11293632&amp;amp;spUserID=MTc0NzU3MzEyMTIxS0&amp;amp;spJobID=1181639680&amp;amp;spReportId=MTE4MTYzOTY4MAS2" target="_blank"&gt;Bob Doll's recent Weekly Commentary&lt;/a&gt;, he writes that
second quarter US domestic growth could reach 3%, and expects corporate earnings to remain strong.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Introducing MomentumStockScans.com!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/06/25/introducing-momentum-stock-scans/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/06/25/introducing-momentum-stock-scans/</id>
    <published>2017-06-24T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-25T12:31:18-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here is a link to my latest project, &lt;a href="http://www.momentumstockscans.com"&gt;MomentumStockScans.com&lt;/a&gt;, a free stock market
scanning tool to help equities traders find the best daily opportunities. Here is a brief introduction video,
more content to follow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pgX9ws8k6uY" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Introducing the US Treasury Yield Curve Website!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/06/07/new-website-us-treasury-yield-curve/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2017/06/07/new-website-us-treasury-yield-curve/</id>
    <published>2017-06-06T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-07T18:24:05-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I haven't been posting to this much, but I created a new website related to trading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ustreasuryyieldcurve.com"&gt;ustreasuryyieldcurve.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be a useful reference for seeing the state of interest rates and what they might signal for the economy.
Worth checking every so often!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
